KeyName,ID,Label_KR,Detail_KR,Option_KR,Label_EN,Detail_EN,Option_EN,Label_JP,Detail_JP,Option_JP
,,,,,,,,,,
0~999 monster,,,,,,,,,,
,1,슬라임,자세히 보면 의외로 귀여운 슬라임입니다. 약하긴 하지만 성장가능성이 높은 몬스터입니다.," @Op1::진화 힌트 : 최대 레벨 달성 후 길드게시판을 확인::Op1
@Op2::슬라임 헌터 처치::Op2",Slime,It's a surprisingly cute slime if you look closely. It's weak- but it's a monster with high potential for growth.," @Op1::Evolution Hint: Check the guild board after maxing out::Op1
@Op2::Slay Slime Hunter::Op2",スライム,よく見るとかわいらしいスライムです。弱いですが、成長の可能性が高いモンスターです。," @Op1::進化ヒント：最大レベル達成後、ギルド掲示板を確認::Op1
@Op2::スライムハンター討伐::Op2"
,2,어스골렘,던전에 마나를 융합해 창조해낸 골렘입니다. 튼튼하고 강해서 모험가들을 상대로 제격이에요. 하지만 조금 한계가 있을지도?," @Op1::진화 힌트 : 최대 레벨 달성 후 길드게시판을 확인::Op1
@Op2::도적 처치::Op2",EarthGolem,It's a golem created by fusing the Dungeon's mana. It's sturdy and strong- perfect for facing adventurers. But it might have some limitations?," @Op1::Evolution Hint: Check the guild board after maxing out::Op1
@Op2::Slay Bandits::Op2",アースゴーレム,ダンジョンにマナを融合させて創造されたゴーレムです。頑丈で強いので、冒険者相手に適していますが、少し限界があるかもしれません。," @Op1::進化ヒント：最大レベル達成後、ギルド掲示板を確認::Op1
 @Op2::盗賊退治::Op2"
,3,머쉬보이,어둡고 습한곳을 좋아하는 버섯몬스터입니다. 높은 공격력을 지녔어요.,,MushBoy,It's a mushroom monster that loves dark and humid places. It has high attack power.,,マッシュボーイ,暗くて湿った場所を好むキノコモンスターです。高い攻撃力を持っています。,
,4,이블아이,매력적인 눈을 지닌 몬스터에요. 생김새때문에 피부가 약할 것 같지만- 실은 엄청 단단하기 때문에 수비용으로 적절합니다.,,EvilEye,It's a monster with captivating eyes. Its appearance might make it seem fragile- but it's actually extremely tough- making it suitable for defense.,,イービルアイ,魅力的な目を持つモンスターです。見た目から皮膚が弱そうに見えますが、実は非常に硬いので、防御用に適しています。,
,5,페어리,순수한 마나의 결정체인 요정 몬스터입니다. 여러방면에서 좋은 밸런스를 가지고 있고- 잠재력도 높은 편입니다.,,Fairy,It's a fairy monster- a pure crystallization of mana. It has a good balance in many areas- and high potential.,,フェアリー,純粋なマナの結晶である妖精モンスターです。様々な面でバランスが良く、潜在能力も高めです。,
,6,살라만드라,원시적인 형태를 지닌 몬스터입니다. 불을 내뿜어 적을 공격합니다. 종족 특성으로 적을 위압하여 빨리 지치게 만들어요.,,Salamandra,It's a monster with a primitive form. It breathes fire to attack enemies. Its racial trait allows it to intimidate enemies and make them tire quickly.,,サラマンダー,原始的な形態を持つモンスターです。火を吐いて敵を攻撃します。種族特性で敵を威圧し、早く疲れさせます。,
,7,그레이하운드,친근감이 느껴지는 늑대형 몬스터입니다. 매우 용맹하고 재빠른 몸놀림을 지녔어요.,,GreyHound,It's a friendly wolf-like monster. It's very brave and agile.,,グレイハウンド,親しみやすい狼型モンスターです。非常に勇敢で素早い動きを持っています。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,501,블러디 슬라임,슬라임의 진화 형태인 블러디 슬라임입니다. 겉으로 보기엔 비슷해 보여도 상당히 강력해졌습니다.,,Bloody Slime,It's the evolved form of a slime- a Bloody Slime. It may look similar on the outside- but it has become considerably more powerful.,,ブラッディスライム,スライムの進化形態であるブラッディスライムです。外見は似ていても、かなり強力になっています。,
,502,플레임 골렘,어스 골렘의 진화 형태인 플레임 골렘입니다. 더 튼튼하고 더 강해졌습니다.,,FlameGolem,It's the evolved form of an Earth Golem- a Flame Golem. It's even sturdier and stronger.,,フレイムゴーレム,アースゴーレムの進化形態であるフレイムゴーレムです。より頑丈で、より強くなっています。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,991,초보자 던전 마스터,모험레벨은 낮아도 던전 지식은 상당한 편이에요.,,Novice Dungeon Master,Their adventure level is low- but they have quite a bit of Dungeon knowledge.,,見習いダンジョンマスター,冒険レベルは低くてもダンジョンの知識はかなりのものです。,
,992,초보자 던전 마스터,모험레벨은 낮아도 던전 지식은 상당한 편이에요.,,Novice Dungeon Master,Their adventure level is low- but they have quite a bit of Dungeon knowledge.,,見習いダンジョンマスター,冒険レベルは低くてもダンジョンの知識はかなりのものです。,
,993,초보자 던전 마스터,모험레벨은 낮아도 던전 지식은 상당한 편이에요.,,Novice Dungeon Master,Their adventure level is low- but they have quite a bit of Dungeon knowledge.,,見習いダンジョンマスター,冒険レベルは低くてもダンジョンの知識はかなりのものです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
1000~1999 npc,,,,,,,,,,
,1000,약초꾼,던전에서 나오는 약초나 풀들을 채취해서 마을과 길드에 공급해주는 역할을 합니다.,,Herbalist,They gather herbs and plants from the Dungeon and supply them to the village and guild.,,薬草採集人,ダンジョンで生える薬草や草を採取し、町やギルドに供給する役割を果たします。,
,1001,베테랑 약초꾼,약초꾼을 업으로 오랜기간 일한 숙련자입니다.,,Veteran Herbalist,An experienced herbalist who has been in the profession for a long time.,,ベテラン薬草採集人,長期間薬草採集を生業としてきた熟練者です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1100,광부,던전에서 생성되는 다양한 광물을 캐내서 마을과 길드에 공급해주는 역할을 합니다.,,Miner,They mine various minerals generated in the Dungeon and supply them to the village and guild.,,鉱夫,ダンジョンで生成される様々な鉱物を採掘し、町やギルドに供給する役割を果たします。,
,1101,베테랑 광부,광물캐기 숙련자입니다. 더 오래 효율적으로 일 할 수 있습니다.,,Veteran Miner,An experienced miner. They can work more efficiently for longer periods.,,ベテラン鉱夫,鉱物採掘の熟練者です。より長時間効率的に作業ができます。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1200,초보 모험가,모험가가 된지 얼마 안된 새내기 모험가입니다. 나름 모험가라서 자원보단 몬스터와 보물에 관심이 있습니다.,,Adventurer,They recently became an adventurer. As an adventurer- they're more interested in monsters and treasure than resources.,,駆け出し冒険者,冒険者になってからあまり経っていない新米冒険者です。冒険者なりに資源よりもモンスターと宝物に関心があります。,
,1201,이름있는 모험가,꽤 이름있는 모험가입니다. 전투 능력과 상황판단 능력 등 새내기 모험가와는 비교할 수 없어요.,,Experienced Adventurer,They're a quite famous adventurer. Their combat abilities and situational judgment are incomparable to novice adventurers.,,名の知れた冒険者,かなり名の知れた冒険者です。戦闘能力や状況判断能力など、新米冒険者とは比べ物になりません。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1300,엘프,자연에 살고 마나 친화력이 높은 종족입니다. 약초에 관한 지식이 많으며 기본적인 전투력도 갖추고 있습니다.,,Elf,They're a race that lives in nature and has a high affinity for mana. They have extensive knowledge about herbs and possess basic combat abilities.,,エルフ,自然に生き、マナ親和性の高い種族です。薬草に関する知識が豊富で、基本的な戦闘力も備えています。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1400,위저드,마법과 물질- 기타 흥미로운 것들을 탐구하는 마법사입니다. 마법의 파괴력이 높기 때문에 상당히 위험합니다.,,Wizard,A wizard who explores magic- matter- and other interesting things. Their magic is highly destructive- making them quite dangerous.,,ウィザード,魔法と物質、その他興味深いものを探求する魔法使いです。魔法の破壊力が高いため、非常に危険です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1800,슬라임 헌터,길드의 퀘스트를 받고 출동한 몬스터 헌터,,Slime Hunter,A monster hunter dispatched by the guild to take on a quest,,スライムハンター,ギルドのクエストを受けて出動したモンスターハンター,
,1801,뒷골목 도적,길드에서 골렘의 핵이 비싼값에 거래된다는 것을 듣고 온 뒷골목 출신 도적,,Back Alley Bandits,A back-alley thug who came after hearing that the guild is buying Golem cores at a premium,,裏路地の盗賊,ギルドでゴーレムの核が高値で取引されていると聞いて来た裏路地出身の盗賊,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1903,새내기 모험가,방금 모험가가 된 새내기 모험가입니다. 나름 모험가라서 자원보단 몬스터와 보물에 관심이 있습니다.,,Newbie adventures,They recently became an adventurer. As an adventurer- they're more interested in monsters and treasure than resources.,,新米冒険者,冒険者になったばかりの新米です。冒険者なりに資源よりもモンスターと宝物に関心があります。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1908,혈기왕성한 모험가,초보자 던전을 답파하여 스승의 인정을 받으려하는 모험가,,Bloodthirsty Adventurer,An adventurer trying to earn their master's recognition by conquering the Novice Dungeon,,血気盛んな冒険者,初心者ダンジョンを踏破して師匠の認定を得ようとする冒険者,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1910,고블린,던전의 모든 자원을 탐내는 고블린입니다.,,Goblin,A goblin coveting all resources in the dungeon.,,ゴブリン,ダンジョンの全ての資源を欲しがるゴブリンです。,
,1911,욕심많은 고블린,던전의 모든 자원을 탐내는 고블린입니다.,,Greedy Goblin,A goblin coveting all resources in the dungeon.,,欲張りゴブリン,ダンジョンの全ての資源を欲しがるゴブリンです。,
,1912,탐욕스런 고블린,던전의 모든 자원을 탐내는 고블린입니다.,,Avaricious Goblin,A goblin coveting all resources in the dungeon.,,強欲なゴブリン,ダンジョンの全ての資源を欲しがるゴブリンです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1914,던전의 재앙,어디선가 나타난 정체 모를 생명체. 던전의 모든 것을 파괴한다.,,Catastrophe of the dungeon,a mysterious creature that appeared out of nowhere. It destroys everything in the dungeon.,,ダンジョンの災厄,どこからか現れた正体不明の生命体。ダンジョンの全てを破壊する。,
,1915,은퇴한 영웅,던전을 조사하러온 과거 영웅 출신의 모험가,,Retired Heroes,A former legendary adventurer who has come to investigate the Dungeon,,引退した英雄,ダンジョンを調査しに来た過去の英雄出身の冒険者,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1920,피의 노래 리더,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 리더 겸 검사입니다.,,BloodSong Leader,Famous party BloodSong's leader and swordsman.,,ブラッドソングのリーダー,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」のリーダー兼剣士です。,
,1921,피의 노래 수호자,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 전위를 담당하는 수호자입니다.,,BloodSong Guardian,Famous party BloodSong's vanguard guardian.,,ブラッドソングの守護者,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」の前衛を担当する守護者です。,
,1922,피의 노래 위저드,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 공격을 담당하는 위저드입니다.,,BloodSong Wizard,Famous party BloodSong's attacking wizard.,,ブラッドソングのウィザード,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」の攻撃を担当するウィザードです。,
,1923,피의 노래 레인저,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 후위을 담당하는 레인저입니다.,,BloodSong Ranger,Famous party BloodSong's rearguard ranger.,,ブラッドソングのレンジャー,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」の後衛を担当するレンジャーです。,
,1924,피의 노래 리더,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 리더 겸 검사입니다.,,BloodSong Leader,Famous party BloodSong's leader and swordsman.,,ブラッドソングのリーダー,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」のリーダー兼剣士です。,
,1925,피의 노래 수호자,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 전위를 담당하는 수호자입니다.,,BloodSong Guardian,Famous party BloodSong's vanguard guardian.,,ブラッドソングの守護者,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」の前衛を担当する守護者です。,
,1926,피의 노래 위저드,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 공격을 담당하는 위저드입니다.,,BloodSong Wizard,Famous party BloodSong's attacking wizard.,,ブラッドソングのウィザード,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」の攻撃を担当するウィザードです。,
,1927,피의 노래 레인저,유명한 파티 피의 노래의 후위을 담당하는 레인저입니다.,,BloodSong Ranger,Famous party BloodSong's rearguard ranger.,,ブラッドソングのレンジャー,有名なパーティー「ブラッドソング」の後衛を担当するレンジャーです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1930,길드 간부,길드에서 파견한 조사단의 분대장입니다.,,Guild Officer,The squad leader of the investigation team dispatched from the guild.,,ギルド幹部,ギルドから派遣された調査団の分隊長です。,
,1931,길드 간부,길드에서 파견한 조사단의 분대장입니다.,,Guild Officer,The squad leader of the investigation team dispatched from the guild.,,ギルド幹部,ギルドから派遣された調査団の分隊長です。,
,1932,영웅 [블루나이트],길드에서 파견한 조사단의 총대장입니다. 현재의 영웅이며 [블루나이트] 라고 불립니다.,,Hero [BlueKnight],The commander in chief of the investigation team dispatched from the guild. The current hero- and called [BlueKnight].,,英雄［ブルーナイト］,ギルドから派遣された調査団の総隊長です。現在の英雄であり、［ブルーナイト］と呼ばれています。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,1941,길드 병사,길드에서 파견한 조사단의 병사입니다.,,Guild Soldier,A soldier of the investigation team dispatched from the guild.,,ギルド兵士,ギルドから派遣された調査団の兵士です。,
,1942,길드 전투원,길드에서 파견한 조사단의 전투원입니다. 병사보다 좀 더 전투 경험이 많습니다.,,Guild Combatant,A combatant of the investigation team dispatched from the guild. More battle experience than soldiers.,,ギルド戦闘員,ギルドから派遣された調査団の戦闘員です。兵士よりも戦闘経験が豊富です。,
,1943,길드 정예병,길드에서 파견한 조사단의 정예병입니다. 한 명 한 명이 매우 강한 전투력을 가지고 있습니다.,,Guild Elite,An elite of the investigation team dispatched from the guild. Each one has very strong combat power.,,ギルド精鋭兵,ギルドから派遣された調査団の精鋭兵です。一人一人が非常に強い戦闘力を持っています。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
2000~2999 facility_Interaction,,,,,,,,,,
,2000,하급 약초,흔한 약초입니다. 소량이지만 마나를 머금고 있고 던전에서만 얻을 수 있어 인기는 많습니다.,,Lower level herbs,It's a common herb. Although in small quantities- it contains mana and is popular since it can only be obtained from Dungeons.,,下級薬草,一般的な薬草です。少量ですがマナを含んでおり、ダンジョンでしか手に入らないため人気があります。,
,2001,상급 약초,꽤 귀한 약초입니다. 고급 포션의 재료로 사용된다고 하네요.,,High level herbs,It's a quite rare herb. It's said to be used as an ingredient for high-grade potions.,,上級薬草,かなり貴重な薬草です。高級ポーションの材料として使用されるそうです。,
,2002,마나 무,마나를 지닌 무입니다. 최고급 식재료로 사용되며 기타 여러 합성에도 사용됩니다.,,Mana radish,It's a radish containing mana. It's used as a top-grade food ingredient and in various other compounds.,,マナ大根,マナを宿した大根です。最高級の食材として使用され、その他様々な合成にも使用されます。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2004,던전 고사리,오래전부터 존재했던 양치식물입니다. 가끔씩 대량으로 발생하여 모험가들의 진행을 막기도 합니다.,,Dungeon fern,An ancient fern that has been around for ages. Occasionally occurs in large numbers- blocking adventurers' progress.,,ダンジョンシダ,古くから存在するシダ植物です。たまに大量に発生し、冒険者の進行を妨げることもあります。,
,2005,활력초,매우 드물게 자라나는 약초입니다. 자양강장제- 활력 포션 등에 사용하며 가치가 높습니다.,,Vigor Herb,A medicinal herb that grows very rarely. It is used in vigor potions and is highly valued.,,活力草,非常に稀に育つ薬草です。滋養強壮剤・活力ポーションなどに使用され、価値が高いです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2100,흔한 바위,흔한 던전의 바위입니다. 그렇지만 지상의 바위와는 완전히 다른 물질이에요.,,Common Rock,It's a common rock from the Dungeon. But it's a completely different material from rocks on the surface.,,一般的な岩,一般的なダンジョンの岩です。しかし、地上の岩とは全く異なる物質です。,
,2101,모래바위,쉽게 부서져 모래가 되는 바위입니다. 마나를 가지고 있어 쉽게 뭉쳐지고 물과 잘 섞여 쓰임새가 많아요.,,Sandstone,It's a rock that easily crumbles into sand. It contains mana- making it easily moldable and mixable with water- giving it many uses.,,砂岩,簡単に崩れて砂になる岩です。マナを含んでいるため簡単に固まり、水とよく混ざるので用途が多いです。,
,2102,단단한 바위,단단한 바위입니다. 튼튼해서 부수려면 꽤나 많은 체력이 필요할 거에요. 건축재료로 사용되어 인기가 많습니다.,,Hard rock,It's a sturdy rock. It's so tough that you'd need quite a bit of stamina to break it. It's popular as a construction material.,,硬い岩,硬い岩です。頑丈なので壊すにはかなりの体力が必要でしょう。建築材料として使用され、人気があります。,
,2103,마나 철광석,순도가 높은 철을 포함하고 있는 철광석입니다. 무기를 만들 때도 쓰이고 각종 장신구에도 쓰여요.,,Mana Ironstone,It's an iron ore containing high-purity iron. It's used for making weapons and various pieces of jewelry.,,マナ鉄鉱石,純度の高い鉄を含む鉄鉱石です。武器を作る際にも使われ、各種装飾品にも使用されます。,
,2104,석탄,불이 잘 붙는 석탄입니다. 마나를 먹은 석탄은 화력도 유지력도 훨씬 길기 때문에 지상에선 고급 연료입니다.,,Coal,It's a coal that ignites easily. Coal infused with mana has much greater heat output and duration- making it a premium fuel on the surface.,,石炭,火がよく付く石炭です。マナを含んだ石炭は火力も持続力もはるかに長いため、地上では高級燃料です。,
,2105,다이아몬드,매우 귀한 물질인 다이아몬드입니다. 마나의 순도가 높기때문에 마법무기의 핵심 부분이에요. 매우 단단하기 때문에 캐기도 힘들어요.,,Diamond,It's the extremely rare material- diamond. Its high mana purity makes it the core component of magical weapons. It's also extremely hard- making it difficult to mine.,,ダイヤモンド,非常に貴重な物質であるダイヤモンドです。マナの純度が高いため、魔法武器の核心部分に使用されます。非常に硬いため、採掘も困難です。,
,2106,루비,은은한 붉은빛의 내는 루비원석입니다. 장식품이나 관상용으로 많이 거래됩니다.,,Ruby,A ruby gemstone with a faint red glow. Widely traded for ornaments and viewing.,,ルビー,淡い赤色を放つルビー原石です。装飾品や観賞用として多く取引されます。,
,2107,룬스톤,마법 룬 문자가 새겨진 희귀한 원석입니다. 상위 클래스 마법을 위해 꼭 필요한 재료이므로 고가에 거래됩니다.,,Runestone,A rare gemstone engraved with magic rune characters. Essential for higher class magic- so it's traded at a high price.,,ルーンストーン,魔法のルーン文字が刻まれた希少な原石です。上位クラスの魔法に必要不可欠な材料のため、高価で取引されます。,
,2108,크리스탈,투명하고 흠이 적은 맑은 크리스탈입니다. 크기와 형태에 따라 가격이 천차만별이에요.,,Crystal,A clear crystal with few flaws. The price varies greatly depending on the size and shape.,,クリスタル,透明で欠陥の少ないきれいなクリスタルです。大きさや形状によって価格が千差万別です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2200,골든 소드,금으로 만들어진 검입니다. 보기엔 멋져보이지만 실제 사용은 어렵고 장식용 입니다.,,Golden Sword,A sword made of gold. It looks impressive but is difficult to use and is for decorative purposes.,,ゴールデンソード,金で作られた剣です。見た目は素晴らしいですが、実際の使用は難しく装飾用です。,
,2201,모험가 소드,적당한 무게와 균형으로 실제 사용이 가능한 검입니다.,,Adventurer's Sword,A sword that is actually usable due to its appropriate weight and balance.,,冒険者の剣,適度な重量とバランスで実際に使用できる剣です。,
,2202,불의 칼,불의 기운이 깃든 검입니다.,,Sword of Fire,A sword imbued with the essence of fire.,,炎の剣,炎の気が宿った剣です。,
,2203,독의 칼,독이 묻어있는 검입니다.,,Sword of Poison,A sword coated with poison.,,毒の剣,毒が塗られている剣です。,
,2204,대거,짧지만 매우 날카로운 대거입니다.,,Dagger,A short but very sharp dagger.,,ダガー,短いですが非常に鋭いダガーです。,
,2205,세이버,사용하기 좋아보이는 세이버입니다.,,Saber,A saber that looks easy to use.,,セイバー,使いやすそうなセイバーです。,
,2206,크리스탈 소드,크리스탈로 된 검입니다. 의식용으로 사용됩니다.,,Crystal Sword,A sword made of crystal. It is used for ceremonial purposes.,,クリスタルソード,クリスタルでできた剣です。儀式用に使用されます。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2210,매직 링,모험가들이 던전을 탐색하는 가장 큰 이유가 되는 보물입니다.,,Magic Ring,It's treasure- the biggest reason adventurers explore Dungeons.,,マジックリング,冒険者たちがダンジョンを探索する最大の理由となる宝物です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2220,마법사의 모자,모험가들이 던전을 탐색하는 가장 큰 이유가 되는 보물입니다.,,Wizard's Hat,It's treasure- the biggest reason adventurers explore Dungeons.,,魔法使いの帽子,冒険者たちがダンジョンを探索する最大の理由となる宝物です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2230,마법 스크롤,모험가들이 던전을 탐색하는 가장 큰 이유가 되는 보물입니다.,,Magic Scroll,It's treasure- the biggest reason adventurers explore Dungeons.,,魔法の巻物,冒険者たちがダンジョンを探索する最大の理由となる宝物です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2240,천상의 하프,제대로 연주한다면 아무리 먼 거리라도 들린다고 하는 희귀 아티팩트 입니다.,,Celestial Harp,It's a rare artifact that is said to be audible from any distance if played properly.,,天上のハープ,正しく演奏すれば、どんなに遠い距離でも聞こえるという希少なアーティファクトです。,
,2241,마법의 모래시계,시간의 흐름에 간섭할 수 있는 희귀 아티팩트 입니다.,,Magic Hourglass,It's a rare artifact that can interfere with the flow of time.,,魔法の砂時計,時の流れに干渉できる希少なアーティファクトです。,
,2242,요술램프,소원을 들어주는 전설의 요술램프 입니다.,,Magic Lamp,It's the legendary lamp that grants wishes.,,魔法のランプ,願いを叶えてくれるという伝説の魔法のランプです。,
,2243,진실의 거울,비춘것의 진실된 모습을 드러내게 만드는 희귀 아티팩트 입니다.,,Mirror of Truth,It's a rare artifact that reveals the true nature of anything it shines upon.,,真実の鏡,映したものの真の姿を現す希少なアーティファクトです。,
,2244,평화의 리라,평화를 불러온다고 알려진 전설의 리라입니다.,,Lira of Peace,A legendary lyre known to bring peace.,,平和のリラ,平和をもたらすと言われる伝説のリラです。,
,2245,해왕의 진주,고대부터 바닷속에 존재했던 보물인 해왕의 진주입니다.,,Sea King's Pearl,A treasure of the sea king that has existed in the ocean since ancient times.,,海王の真珠,古代から海底に存在していた宝物である海王の真珠です。,
,2246,황금 잔,황금으로 만들어져 매우 값어치가 높은 물건이에요.,,Golden Goblet,An item made of gold that is very valuable,,黄金の杯,黄金で作られた非常に価値の高い物です。,
,2247,고대 금화,과거에 사용되었던 금화입니다. 실제 가치는 아무도 알 수 없어요.,,Ancient Gold Coins,Ancient gold coins used in the past. Their actual value is unknown to anyone.,,古代の金貨,過去に使用されていた金貨です。実際の価値は誰にもわかりません。,
,2248,봉인된 십자가,무언가 강한 존재를 봉인할 때 사용된 십자가입니다.,,Sealed Cross,A cross used to seal a powerful entity.,,封印された十字架,何か強力な存在を封印する際に使用された十字架です。,
,2249,운명의 주사위,굴리는 대로 운명이 정해진다고 하는 무서운 주사위입니다.,,Dice of Fate,Scary dice that determine fate when rolled.,,運命のサイコロ,振った通りに運命が決まるという恐ろしいサイコロです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2250,황금 왕관,모험가들이 던전을 탐색하는 가장 큰 이유가 되는 보물입니다.,,Golden Crown,It's treasure- the biggest reason adventurers explore Dungeons.,,黄金の王冠,冒険者たちがダンジョンを探索する最大の理由となる宝物です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2260,보물상자 A,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest A,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 A,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2261,보물상자 B,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest B,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 B,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2262,보물상자 C,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest C,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 C,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2263,보물상자 D,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest D,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 D,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2264,보물상자 E,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest E,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 E,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2265,보물상자 F,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest F,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 F,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2266,보물상자 G,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest G,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 G,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2267,보물상자 H,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest H,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 H,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2268,보물상자 I,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest I,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 I,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2269,보물상자 J,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest J,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 J,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2270,보물상자 K,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest K,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 K,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,2271,보물상자 L,무엇이 들어있는지 모르는 상자입니다. 하지만 모험가라면 열어보지 않고는 참을 수 없을 거예요.,,Treasure Chest L,A chest whose contents are unknown. But an adventurer wouldn't be able to resist opening it-,,宝箱 L,中身が分からない箱です。しかし、冒険者なら開けずにはいられないでしょう。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2400,맑은 우물,모험가가 쉴 수 있는 우물입니다. 마시면 힘이 나서 좀 더 활동할 수 있어요. \다 사용하면 다시 보충해야 합니다. ,,Pure well,A well where adventurers can rest. \When you drink from it- you'll feel energized and be able to do more. \When you use it up- you'll need to replenish it. ,,澄んだ井戸,冒険者が休憩できる井戸です。飲むと力がわいて、さらに活動できます。\n使い切ったら再度補充する必要があります。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2901,신비로운 알,신비한 분위기를 지닌 알입니다. 계약기간 동안 지켜야 합니다.,,Mysterious Egg,An egg with a mysterious atmosphere. Must be kept during the contract period.,,神秘の卵,神秘的な雰囲気を持つ卵です。契約期間中は守らなければなりません。,
,2902,신비로운 알,신비한 분위기를 지닌 알입니다. 계약기간 동안 지켜야 합니다.,,Mysterious Egg,An egg with a mysterious atmosphere. Must be kept during the contract period.,,神秘の卵,神秘的な雰囲気を持つ卵です。契約期間中は守らなければなりません。,
,2903,신비로운 알,신비한 분위기를 지닌 알입니다. 계약기간 동안 지켜야 합니다.,,Mysterious Egg,An egg with a mysterious atmosphere. Must be kept during the contract period.,,神秘の卵,神秘的な雰囲気を持つ卵です。契約期間中は守らなければなりません。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,2910,신비로운 알,신비한 분위기를 지닌 알입니다. 계약기간 동안 지켜야 합니다. 따듯한 마나가 감돌고 있습니다.,,Mysterious Egg,An egg with a mysterious atmosphere. Must be kept during the contract period. Warm mana is circulating.,,神秘の卵,神秘的な雰囲気を持つ卵です。契約期間中は守らなければなりません。温かいマナが漂っています。,
,2911,신비로운 알,신비한 분위기를 지닌 알입니다. 계약기간 동안 지켜야 합니다.,,Mysterious Egg,An egg with a mysterious atmosphere. Must be kept during the contract period.,,神秘の卵,神秘的な雰囲気を持つ卵です。契約期間中は守らなければなりません。,
,2912,신비로운 알,신비한 분위기를 지닌 알입니다. 계약기간 동안 지켜야 합니다.,,Mysterious Egg,An egg with a mysterious atmosphere. Must be kept during the contract period.,,神秘の卵,神秘的な雰囲気を持つ卵です。契約期間中は守らなければなりません。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
3000~3999 facility_Event,,,,,,,,,,
,3000,출구,지상으로 향하는 출입구 입니다.,,Exit,It's the entrance leading to the surface.,,出口,地上へ向かう出入り口です。,
,3001,입구,지하로 향하는 출입구입니다.,,Entrance,It's the entrance leading underground.,,入口,地下へ向かう出入り口です。,
,3002,전이진,던전의 숨겨진 공간으로 이동할 수 있는 전이진입니다.,,Portal,It's a warp gate that allows movement to the Dungeon's hidden spaces.,,転移陣,ダンジョンの隠された空間へ移動できる転移陣です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,3200,낙하 함정,뻔히 보이는 함정이지만 걸린다면 꽤 효과가 있을 거예요.,,Falling trap,It's an obvious trap- but if triggered- it can have quite an effect.,,落とし穴,一目で分かる罠ですが、引っかかれば結構効果がありそうです。,
,3201,강화 낙하 함정,뻔히 보이는 함정이지만 걸린다면 꽤 효과가 있을 거예요. 좀 더 여러번 사용 가능합니다.,,Enhanced Falling trap,It's an obvious trap- but if triggered- it can have quite an effect. It can be used a few more times.,,強化落とし穴,一目で分かる罠ですが、引っかかれば結構効果がありそうです。もう少し何回も使用できます。,
,3202,송곳 함정,무시무시한 송곳이 올라오는 함정이에요. 모르고 위를 지나간다면 크게 다칠 거예요.,,Awl trap,It's a terrifying trap with spikes that rise from the floor. If you unknowingly walk over it- you'll be seriously injured.,,トゲの罠,恐ろしいトゲが飛び出す罠です。知らずに上を通れば大怪我をしそうです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,3500,건설 불가 타일,,,X,,,建設不可タイル,,
,3501,Obstacle_Wall,,,Obstacle_Wall,,,Obstacle_Wall,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,3503,RemoveableObstacle,,,RemoveableObstacle,,,RemoveableObstacle,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,3531,장애물_3층_1,,,Obstacle_3_1,,,障害物_3階_1,,
,3532,장애물_3층_2,,,Obstacle_3_2,,,障害物_3階_2,,
,3533,장애물_3층_3,,,Obstacle_3_3,,,障害物_3階_3,,
,3534,장애물_3층_4,,,Obstacle_3_4,,,障害物_3階_4,,
,3535,장애물_3층_5,,,Obstacle_3_5,,,障害物_3階_5,,
,3536,장애물_3층_6,,,Obstacle_3_6,,,障害物_3階_6,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,3900,금빛 천사상,황금으로 만들어진 천사상입니다. 기도를 올리면 소량의 골드를 얻습니다.,,Golden Angel Statue,It's an angel statue made of gold. Praying to it rewards you with a small amount of gold.,,金色の天使像,黄金で作られた天使像です。祈りを捧げると少量のゴールドを得られます。,
,3901,은빛 천사상,순은으로 만들어진 천사상입니다. 기도를 올리면 소량의 마나를 얻습니다.,,Silver Angel Statue,It's an angel statue made of silver. Praying to it rewards you with a small amount of mana.,,銀色の天使像,純銀で作られた天使像です。祈りを捧げると少量のマナを得られます。,
,3902,신뢰의 조각상,신뢰가 느껴지는 동물을 닮은 조각상입니다.,,Sculpture of Trust,A sculpture resembling an animal that exudes an atmosphere of trust.,,信頼の彫像,信頼を感じさせる動物に似た彫像です。,
,3903,파괴의 조각상,강한 힘과 파괴의 충동이 느껴지는 조각상입니다.,,Sculpture of Destruction,A sculpture that exudes a strong force and the urge for destruction.,,破壊の彫像,強い力と破壊の衝動を感じさせる彫像です。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
5000~6999 contents,,,,,,,,,,
,5000,작은 약초밭,하급 약초가 자라나는 약초밭을 설치합니다. 흔하긴 해도 마나를 지니고 있기 때문에 쓰임새는 많은 편이에요.,,Small herb garden,It installs a herb garden where low-grade herbs grow. Although common- they contain mana- so they have many uses.,,小さな薬草畑,下級薬草が育つ薬草畑を設置します。ありふれていますが、マナを持っているため用途は多いです。,
,5001,큰 약초밭,하급 약초가 자라나는 약초밭을 설치합니다. 흔하긴 해도 마나를 지니고 있기 때문에 쓰임새는 많은 편이에요.,,Large herb garden,It installs a herb garden where low-grade herbs grow. Although common- they contain mana- so they have many uses.,,大きな薬草畑,下級薬草が育つ薬草畑を設置します。ありふれていますが、マナを持っているため用途は多いです。,
,5002,고급 약초밭,고급 약초가 자라나는 약초밭을 설치합니다. 쉽게 구할 수 없는 귀한 약초입니다. 마나 효율이 높아요.,,High level herb garden,It installs a herb garden where high-grade herbs grow. These are rare herbs that are not easily obtained. They are highly mana-efficient.,,高級薬草畑,高級薬草が育つ薬草畑を設置します。簡単に手に入らない貴重な薬草です。マナ効率が高いです。,
,5003,마나 무밭,마나를 지닌 무입니다. 최고급 식재료로도 사용이 되며 기타 여러 합성에 재료로 사용됩니다.,,Mana radish Field,It's a radish containing mana. It's used as a top-grade food ingredient and in various other compounds.,,マナ大根畑,マナを宿した大根です。最高級食材としても使用され、その他様々な合成の材料としても使用されます。,
,5004,고사리의 벽,던전 고사리를 대량으로 설치합니다. 하나하나의 효과는 약해도 모험가들의 발을 붙잡는데는 효과적입니다.,,Fern Wall,Sets up a large amount of dungeon ferns. Though each has a weak effect- they are effective at hindering adventurers' movements.,,シダの壁,ダンジョンシダを大量に設置します。一つ一つの効果は弱いですが、冒険者の足を止めるのに効果的です。,
,5005,활력초밭,활력초를 설치합니다. 잘못하면 쉽게 손상되기 때문에 채집하는데 많은 시간이 필요합니다.,,Vital Herb Field,Sets up vital herbs. They are easily damaged if handled improperly- requiring a lot of time to gather.,,活力草畑,活力草を設置します。扱いを間違えると簡単に損傷するため、採集には多くの時間がかかります。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5100,작은 광맥,유용한 물질을 얻을 수 있는 광맥을 설치합니다. 여러 광물이 섞여있어요.,,Small Ore Vein,Sets up an ore vein from which useful materials can be obtained. It contains a mix of various minerals.,,小さな鉱脈,有用な物質を得ることができる鉱脈を設置します。様々な鉱物が混ざっています。,
,5101,큰 광맥,유용한 물질을 얻을 수 있는 광맥을 설치합니다. 여러 광물이 섞여있어요.,,Large Ore Vein,Sets up a larger ore vein from which useful materials can be obtained. It contains a mix of various minerals.,,大きな鉱脈,有用な物質を得ることができるより大きな鉱脈を設置します。様々な鉱物が混ざっています。,
,5102,루비 광맥,루비를 얻을 수 있는 광맥입니다. 꽤나 단단하기 때문에 시간을 들여 채굴해야 합니다.,,Ruby Ore Vein,An ore vein where rubies can be obtained. It is quite hard- requiring time to mine.,,ルビー鉱脈,ルビーを得ることができる鉱脈です。かなり硬いため、時間をかけて採掘する必要があります。,
,5103,석탄 광맥,석탄을 캘 수 있는 광맥입니다. 쉽고 빠른 채굴이 가능합니다.,,Coal Ore Vein,An ore vein where coal can be mined. It allows for easy and quick mining.,,石炭鉱脈,石炭を採掘できる鉱脈です。簡単かつ迅速に採掘が可能です。,
,5104,마나 철광맥,순도 높은 마나 철광석을 다량 포함하고 있는 검은 크리스탈을 설치합니다.,,Mana Iron Ore Vein,Sets up a black crystal containing a large amount of high-purity mana iron ore.,,マナ鉄鉱脈,純度の高いマナ鉄鉱石を多量に含む黒いクリスタルを設置します。,
,5105,크리스탈의 벽,크리스탈로 이루어진 벽을 설치합니다. 쓸모는 많지만 채굴 난이도는 높은 편입니다.,,Crystal Wall,Sets up a wall made of crystal. It has many uses but is difficult to mine.,,クリスタルの壁,クリスタルでできた壁を設置します。用途は多いが、採掘の難易度は高いです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5200,낙하 함정,고전식 발밑 함정을 설치합니다. 발동되면 시간과 체력에 피해를 줄 수 있어요.,,Falling trap,It installs a classic pit trap. If triggered- it can damage your time and stamina.,,落とし穴,古典的な足元の罠を設置します。作動すると時間と体力にダメージを与えられます。,
,5201,강화 낙하 함정,고전식 발밑 함정을 설치합니다. 기존의 함정보다 조금 더 효과가 강해졌어요.,,Enhanced Falling trap,It installs a classic pit trap. It's slightly more effective than the previous trap.,,強化落とし穴,古典的な足元の罠を設置します。既存の罠よりも少し効果が強くなっています。,
,5202,송곳 함정,바닥에서 송곳이 올라오는 무시무시한 함정을 설치합니다. 발동되면 큰 피해를 입힙니다.,,Awl trap,It installs a terrifying trap with spikes that rise from the floor. If triggered- it will inflict severe damage.,,トゲの罠,床からトゲが飛び出す恐ろしい罠を設置します。作動すると大きなダメージを与えます。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5300,쓸만한 무기,모험가들이 좋아할만한 무기를 설치합니다. \모험가에게 발견되면 던전의 인기도나 위험도가 조금 올라요.,,Useful Swords,Sets up weapons that adventurers would like. \If discovered by adventurers- the dungeon's popularity or danger level slightly increases.,,使える武器,冒険者が好みそうな武器を設置します。\冒険者に発見されると、ダンジョンの人気度や危険度が少し上がります。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5310,마법 반지,던전의 마나를 사용해서 만들어낸 마법 반지입니다. 착용자의 마나를 조금 흡수하는 효과가 걸려있습니다. \모험가에게 발견되면 던전의 인기도가 조금 올라요.,,Magic Ring,It's a magic ring created using the Dungeon's mana. It has an effect that slightly absorbs the wearer's mana. \If discovered by adventurers- the Dungeon's popularity will increase slightly.,,魔法の指輪,ダンジョンのマナを使って作り出した魔法の指輪です。着用者のマナを少し吸収する効果がかかっています。\冒険者に発見されるとダンジョンの人気度が少し上がります。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5330,마법 스크롤,고대의 주문이 적힌 스크롤입니다. 고위 마법사들이 마법을 배우기 위해 필요한 아이템으로 인기가 많습니다.,,Magic Scroll,It's a scroll inscribed with ancient spells. It's a popular item needed by high-level mages to learn magic.,,魔法の巻物,古代の呪文が書かれた巻物です。上位魔法使いたちが魔法を学ぶために必要なアイテムとして人気があります。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5340,던전 아티팩트,던전에서만 얻을 수 있는 희귀한 아티팩트 입니다. \어떤 아티팩트가 나올지는 알 수 없습니다. \각기 다른 고유한 힘을 가지고 있어요.,,Dungeon Artifacts,It's a rare artifact that can only be obtained from Dungeons. \You can't know what artifact will appear. \Each one has a unique power.,,ダンジョンアーティファクト,ダンジョンでしか手に入らない希少なアーティファクトです。\どんなアーティファクトが出るかは分かりません。\それぞれ異なる固有の力を持っています。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5360,보물상자,던전 탐색의 즐거움을 주는 보물상자를 만들어냅니다. \어떤 등급의 상자가 나올지- 상자 안에 무엇이 들었을지는 열어보기 전까진 알 수 없어요.,,Treasure Chest,Creates treasure chests that bring the joy of dungeon exploration. \What grade of chest will come out- and what's inside the chest can't be known until it's opened.,,宝箱,ダンジョン探索の楽しみを与える宝箱を作り出します。\どんな等級の箱が出るか、箱の中に何が入っているかは開けてみるまで分かりません。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5400,맑은 우물,모험가가 쉴 수 있는 우물입니다. 마시면 힘이 나서 좀 더 활동할 수 있어요. \모험가가 좀 더 멀리 갈 수 있도록 돕고 더 많은 마나를 얻게 하는 목적의 장치입니다만- 너무 많은 편의를 제공한다면 오히려 위험해질 수 있으니 신중하게 선택해야 합니다.,,Pure well,A well where adventurers can rest. \When you drink from it- you'll feel energized and be able to do more. \They're meant to help adventurers go farther and gain more mana- but they can be dangerous if they provide too much convenience.,,清らかな井戸,冒険者が休める井戸です。飲むと力が湧いてもう少し活動できます。\冒険者がもう少し遠くまで行けるよう助け、より多くのマナを得られるようにする目的の装置ですが、あまりに多くの便宜を提供すれば逆に危険になる可能性があるので、慎重に選択する必要があります。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,5500,입구,입구의 위치를 지정합니다. \입구는 층 당 한개만 존재할 수 있어요. \만약 입구가 없으면 시작시 자동으로 생성됩니다.,,Exit,It designates the location of the entrance. \There can only be one entrance per floor. \If there is no entrance- one will automatically generate at the start.,,入口,入口の位置を指定します。\入口は階層ごとに一つだけ存在できます。\もし入口がなければ開始時に自動的に生成されます。,
,5501,출구,출구의 위치를 지정합니다. \출구는 층 당 한개만 존재할 수 있어요. \만약 출구가 없으면 시작시 자동으로 생성됩니다.,,Entrance,It designates the location of the exit. \There can only be one exit per floor. \If there is no exit- one will automatically generate at the start.,,出口,出口の位置を指定します。\出口は階層ごとに一つだけ存在できます。\もし出口がなければ開始時に自動的に生成されます。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
7000~7999 Technical,,,,,,,,,,
,7000,허브 농장,2일마다 활성화 된 모든 층에 약초를 공급해줍니다. \가끔 좋은 약초가 나올때도 있어요!,,Herb Farm,Every 2 days- it supplies herbs to all activated floors. \Sometimes good herbs can appear!,,ハーブ農場,2日ごとにアクティブな全ての階層に薬草を供給します。\たまに良い薬草が出ることもあります！,
,7001,활력의 오브,매 턴 행동력이 1 늘어납니다. \역시 건강한게 제일이죠.,,Orb of Vitality,Your action points increase by 1 every turn. \Health is the most important- after all.,,活力のオーブ,毎ターン行動力が1増えます。\やはり健康が一番ですね。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,7100,기부함,던전 입구에 기부함을 설치합니다. 사실 말이 기부함이지 입장료를 받는거에요. \많은 인기있는 던전들이 입장료를 받지만 과연 우리 던전도 입장료를 내고서라도 들어올 만한 가치가 있을까요?,,Donation box,It installs a donation box at the Dungeon entrance. Actually- it's not a donation box- it's an entrance fee. \Many popular Dungeons charge an entrance fee- but will our Dungeon be worth paying to enter?,,募金箱,ダンジョン入口に募金箱を設置します。実際のところ募金箱と言っても入場料を取るんです。\多くの人気のあるダンジョンが入場料を取っていますが、果たして私たちのダンジョンも入場料を払ってまで入る価値があるでしょうか？,
,7101,감옥,모험가를 포로로 잡을 수 있는 감옥을 설치합니다. \쓰러트린 일부 모험가들에게서 교섭으로 골드를 뜯어낼 수 있을거에요.,,Prison,It installs a prison capable of capturing adventurers. \You can extort gold from some of the captured adventurers through negotiation.,,牢獄,冒険者を捕虜として捕らえられる牢獄を設置します。\倒した一部の冒険者たちから交渉でゴールドを巻き上げられそうです。,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
,,,,,,,,,,
